Hakan Tek



Universitätsstraße 7, 33615 Bielefeld

PERSONAL PROFILE

An engineer who likes to develop algorithms and software. Developed projects with teammates in the fields of operation research and deep learning, resulting in a TUBITAK award. A paragliding pilot who likes to fly with the student club. A Lieferando biker who loves mountain biking.



EDUCATION

2020 – Present Production Engineering and Management, M.Sc.,

Technische Hochschule Ostwestfalen-Lippe, Lemgo, Germany

University of Trieste (Double degree), Pordenone, Italy

2014 – 2019 Industrial Engineering, B.Sc.,

Izmir University of Economics, Izmir, Turkey (3.09)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan – Sep 2020 R&D Engineer (Full time) / Akar Textile, Izmir, Turkey

Developed an open-source ERP software for production planning and

control. See project here: github.com/AkarTextile/erp4j.git

Apr – Dec 2019 Production Engineer (Full time) / Akar Textile, Izmir, Turkey

Formulated the standard times in Cutting Department and determinate the

operators' performances.

Nov 2018 – Jun 2019 Project Engineering (Intern) / Philip Morris International, Izmir, Turkey

Within the scope of the university graduation project, developed the number of defective products prediction model using machine learning algorithms.

See project here: github.com/hakanttek/SeniorProject.git

Nov 2018 – Feb 2019 Assistant Teacher (Part time) / Izmir University of Economics, Izmir, Turkey

Provided training for Excel to the students and the beginner staffs in Teaching and Learning Center. Developed an Excel macro for item analysis.

Aug – Sep 2018 Manufacturing Systems Engineer (Intern) / Akar Textile, Izmir, Turkey

Wrote a macro which optimally assigning the product models to the lines

using Excel, VBA and Solver.

Jun – Aug 2018 Production Engineer (Intern) / Hugo Boss, ESBAŞ, Izmir, Turkey

Got training about production engineering and personal growth. Wrote a macro for optimally machine layout planning using Excel, VBA and solver.

Jul – Sep 2017 Production Control Engineer (Intern) / Delphi Technologies, Izmir, Turkey

Did an internship in the tugger system project.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Sep 2021 – Present Buddy Student / TH-OWL, Lemgo, Germany

Helping two incoming students to adapt to Germany.

Oct 2017 – Oct 2018 Chairperson / IUE Aviation Club, Izmir, Turkey

Launch the autonomous uav project. Paragliding trainings were organized.

May – Sep 2016 Fundraiser / UNICEF, Izmir, Turkey

Persuaded the people, who walk on the street, into being a supporter.

Hakan Tek

Universitätsstraße 7, 33615 Bielefeld ☐ hakan.tek@stud.th-owl.de | ☐ +49 1573 5687740 | ☐ hakanttek

SKILLS

Vocational IBM ILOG CPLEX Optimization Studio (Advanced), Excel & VBA (Advanced),

EDS(Intermediate), SAP S/4 HANA (Beginner), Teamcenter (Beginner)

Programming Java (Advanced), Python (Intermediate), C# (Intermediate),

SQL (Intermediate), HTML & CSS (Beginner)

Language Turkish (Native), English (Advanced), German (Intermediate)

ACHIEVEMENT

Sep 2020 Encouragement Award – Akar Textile R&D Center

June 2019 Aegean Region Winner – TÜBİTAK 2242 Undergraduate Students Research

Project Competition

June 2019 Paper Acceptance – 39th Operations Research / Industrial Engineering

National Congress

CERTIFICATES

June 2019 39th Operations Research / Industrial Engineering National Congress –

Başkent University (3 Days)

Sep 2019 Teknofest – Republic of Turkey Ministry of Industrial (5 Days)

June 2018 Create Your Future, Design Thinking and Formation Future Vision Workshop

Hugo Boss (13 Hours)

June – July 2018 Object-oriented programming C# – Elginkan Foundation (80 Hours)

Mar 2018 12nd MÜYAK – Anadolu University (3 Days)

Feb 2018 IndEx'18 – Koç University (3 Days)

Sep – Oct 2017 Advanced Excel Course – Elginkan Foundation (56 Hours)

Sep 2017 – Jan 2018 Kaizen, 5S Principles, Benchmarking and 6 Sigma Seminars – Elginkan

Foundation (16 Hours)

Jan 2017 24th ITU EMÖS – Istanbul Technical University (5 Days)

Mar 2016 Zirve'16 – Yaşar University (4 Hours)

HOBBIES

Mountain biking, paragliding, swimming, escape game, crime fiction and science fiction.

REFERENCES

Metin Üyük Electronics Team Supervisor / Philip Morris International, Izmir, Turkey

Office Phone: +90 (232) 488 73 24 Email: Metin.Uyuk@pmi.com

Asst. Prof. G. Reşat Academician / Izmir University of Economics, Izmir, Turkey

Office Phone: +90 (232) 488 84 65 Email: giray.resat@ieu.edu.tr

Hakan Sarper Production Engineer / Hugo Boss, ESBAŞ, Izmir, Turkey

Mobile: +90 533 331 31 13 Email: Hakan_Sarper@hugoboss.com